So in the last lecture we defined our javascript object which should represent our form.
Bu yzden son konferansta formumuzu temsil eden javascript nesnemize meydan okuduk.
Now I want to output that in my render method here,
imdi bunu render yntemimde burada istiyorum.
I want to create all these inputs dynamically. So I'll get rid of them in the render form here for now
Btn bu girdileri dinamik olarak oluturmak istiyorum, bu yzden imdi render formundan bunlardan kurtulacam.
and I now need to first of all turn my order form object here into some kind of array
imdi ncelikle sipari form nesnemizi bir dizi diziye dntrmek zorundaym.
I can loop through, an array where we basically have javascript objects where this key is just one property,
Burada, temel olarak, Diski'nin bir tanmlayc zellik olan yalnzca bir zellik olduu ve ardndan hala Alber
an identifier property and then we also still have the other properties.
zelliklerine sahip olduumuz javascript nesnelerine sahip bir dizi zerinden dng salayabiliriz.
Well we can create such an array relatively simple here,
Burada nispeten basit bir dizi oluturabiliriz.
there are always more than one method, of course here,
Burada her zaman birden fazla yntem vardr.
I'll create my form elements array, a constant which is an empty array and then I will use a for/in loop
Form eleri dizisini bo bir dizi olan bir dizi olutururum ve sonra da bir for
where I get to keys of my
dngs kullanarak benim anahtarlarmn anahtarlarn alacam.
now this.state.orderForm and the key therefore are of course the property names of that object.
imdi bu devlet dzen formu ve anahtar elbette o nesnenin mlkiyet isimleridir.
So the keys are going to be name, street, zipcode and so on
Yani anahtarlar Sokak posta kodu gibi isim olacak.
and if we access order form for a given key, we get these values here on the right side of course.
Ve eer X-ists belirli bir anahtar iin form verirsek, bu deerleri tabii ki sa tarafta elde ederiz.
So with that information, let's go down there and let's create or let's push I should say a new object
Bu yzden bu bilgilere bakalm oraya gidelim ve Portia'y yaratalm veya izin verelim Yeni nesne
to the form elements array,
ateli form eleri dizisi sylemeliyim.
this object should have an id which is the key, because again that is name and so on, these are identifiers
anahtar iin bu durum siparii biiminde olan yaplandrmaya sahip olmaldrlar.
and then it should have the config which is this.state.orderForm for a given key.
Bu nesnenin kimlii bir anahtar niteliinde olmaldr, nk yine ad ve benzeri tanmlayclardr ve daha sonra belirli bir
So this is now the right side of this property
Dolaysyla imdi bu mlkiyetin sa taraf.
so this javascript object, that is what we we'll store in this config property. And of course, you can
Bu javascript nesnesi, bu atma mlknde saklayacamz ey ve elbette mlknze istediiniz
name the config property whatever you want, you can name it set up whatever you want.
ismi istediiniz her eyi verdiinizde adlandrabileceinizi belirtebilirsiniz.
So now we got an array of javascript objects, with that array we can work
imdi, alabildiimiz dizi ile bir dizi javascript nesnesi bulduk.
I can work with it by now creating my form here while looping through all these elements.
Btn bu unsurlar arasnda dng yaparken imdi formumu yaratarak onunla alabilirim.
So I will add curly braces here in the form and now I want to loop through my form elements array with
Bu yzden formda kvrck parantez ekleyeceim ve imdi drt element dizilimimi, tabii ki burada yeni
the map method of course to generate a new array basically, here
bir dizi oluturmak iin harita yntemi ile dnglemek istiyorum.
this will get the individual form element and it just returns some jsx here, the jsx it returns
Bu, dier bireysel form esini alacak ve yalnzca X ve J yanndaki x deerini
of course, it should be my custom input component.
X olarak dndrr ve dndrr, elbette benim zel inport bileenim olmaldr.
And now we can configure it, it should have the elements and the element type.
Ve imdi elemanlar ve eleman trn olmas gerektii gibi yaplandrabiliriz.
Now the element type can be accessed on the form element in my array and there I said that in this config
imdi eleman trne dizilimdeki form esinde eriilebilir ve orada bu atma
property, we would store the right side of our setup,
zelliinde kurulumun sa tarafn saklardm dedim.
so this object.
Yani bu nesne.
So in the config property, this is just another javascript object,
Yani atma zelliinde sadece birka javascript nesnesi var.
there should be the element type property, an element config and value
e tr mlkiyet ve e atmas ve deeri olmaldr.
and these are properties I want to pass on.
Bunlar gemek istediim zellikler.
So in the end what I pass on here is form element, config and then there as I just said, the element type.
Sonunda burada anlattm ey, form esinin kaln olmas ve daha sonra e trnn ayarlanmas.
So just the name we have here, element type, we pass element config and value in the same way,
Dolaysyla sadece burada sahip olduumuz isim element ats ve deerini ayn ekilde geirdik.
so here we passed the element type,
Bylece burada d element trn getik.
now the element config is passed as I just said in the same way with form element config, element
imdi e ierii form esi atma esi atmas ile ayn ekilde
config and the value also is passed like this element,
sylendiim gibi iletilir ve deer de bu e gibi geirilir.
excuse me,
Affedersiniz.
form element, form element config element config.
Form esi form esi akma esi akmas.
Let's get rid of that dummy and put elements here at the top
O kukladan kurtulalm ve elemanlar buraya yerletirelim.
and with that we should dynamically create our input elements.
Ve bununla birlikte, giri elerimizi dinamik olarak oluturmalyz.
Now as always, I forgot my key and right now we're not having an onChange handler,
imdi her zamanki gibi anahtarm unuttum ve u an iin bir deiim ileci sahibi deiliz.
we also right now seem to have issues extracting our placeholder,
Ayrca imdi yer tutucumuzu karmak iin sorunlar yayoruz gibi grnyoruz.
it's an object and not a string
Bu bir cisim deil, bir cisim.
so these are things we have to take care about.
Dolaysyla bunlar bizimle ilgilenmek zorunda olduumuz eyler.
Let's start with the key, for the key,
Anahtarn anahtar ile balayalm.
I'll simply take form element id property we add in our loop here, have a typo here,
Tm basite form unsurunu alalm id zellii ekliyoruz, burada yazm hatas var.
now regarding the missing onChange handler for which I also got an error, we'll take care about this in
imdi de eksik olan onchange ileyicisi ile ilgili bir hata aldm, bununla ilgili
a second.
bir saniye bekleyecektir.
Let's have a look at why we have issues outputting our placeholder though,
Neden kirac olduumuzu ortaya karmakla ilgili sorunlarmz olduunu dnelim.
I've found the error, I'm passing the wrong value, it's not the placeholder,
Hatay buldum ve yanl deerleri geirdim, yer tutucu deil.
the value is wrong. Here of course, this should be config value not element config.
Deer yanl burada elbette ki atma deeri atma deil atma olmal.
Now if that we're outputting the placeholder,
imdi eer yer tutucu ktlyorsa.
this all is working.
Bu her ey alyor.
Now of course, we also have to make sure if we can react to changes and that we also have a way of handling
girdi bileeni var. ve metin alanlarn kullanrz, ancak seilen bir eyi ele almaya alrz.
our dropdown down because right now, this is created incorrectly because of course here we have our switch
imdilik elimizde deiikliklere tepki gsterip gsteremeyeceimizden emin olmalyz ve alr listemizi ele almann bir yolunu bulmamz gerekiyor, nk
statement and the input component, we handle inputs and text areas but we also try to create a select element,
u anda yanl bir ekilde oluturuldu, tabii ki burada switch ifadem ve ele aldmz
we do this here in our set up for delivery method, should be select with options.
Bunu yaptmz yerde kurma yntemimiz iin seeneklerle birlikte semeliyiz.
So let's add or let's adjust our input component to also be able to create that before we then have a
Bu yzden, giri bileenini, verileri nasl alacamzza bir bakmadan nce de
look at how we can actually get the data
tedavi edebilmek iin ekleyelim veya ayarlayalm.
the user enters.
Kullanc girer.